NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- PUBLIC ACCOMMODATIONS
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Williams v. Hot Shoppes, Inc., 1960
  - West Virginia
    - Brown v. County Court of Kanawha County, W.Va., circa 1959
  - Wisconsin
    - Lange v. Rancher, 1953
- RECREATIONAL FACILITIES
  The fund undertook cases which specifically targeted segregated recreational facilities supported by public funds such as parks, beaches, swimming pools, golf courses, and tennis courts because these cases provided a clear and strong challenge to separate-but-equal precepts. Later, the fund brought cases of racial discrimination against privately owned and operated facilities.
  - Florida
    - Youngblood v. Snow, 1955
  - Georgia
    - Woods v. Murrah, 1956
  - Kansas
    - Bailey v. Smith, circa 1953
  - Louisiana
    - Detiege v. New Orleans City Park Improvement Ass'n, 1949-1951
  - Maryland
    - Boyer v. Garrett, 1948
    - Bryant v. Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, 1950
    - Dawson v. Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, Md., 1947-1956
  - Missouri
    - Shields v. City of Chillicothe, 1955
    - Williams v. City of Kansas City, 1951-1953
  - New Jersey
    - Scurry v. Sukup, 1951
    - Valle v. Stengel, 1949
  - South Carolina
    - Clark v. Flory, 1956
    - Commings v. City of Charleston, 1960-1961
    - Walker v. Shaw, 1961-1963
  - Tennessee
    - Easterly v. Dempster, 1952
    - Hart v. Knox County, 1948
  - Texas
    - Beal v. Holcombe, 1951
    - Byars v. White, 1955-1956
    - Fleming v. Garrison, 1955
    - Register v. Sandefer, 1949
  - Virginia
    - Department of Conservation & Dev. v. Tate, 1956
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Camp v. Recreational Bd. for the District of Columbia, 1951
- TRANSPORTATION
  The fund challenged various state laws requiring segregated travel in buses and trains. Suits contended that separate quarters were not equal and also raised jurisdictional questions. The Interstate Commerce Commission (ICC) was eventually vested with the authority to revoke segregation when it impeded interstate commerce, and cases involving segregation on interstate trains and buses were thereafter heard by the ICC. Local transit authorities, mainly city bus and street-car systems, continued to be challenged in the courts.
  - Alabama
    - Jones v. Southeastern Greyhound Lines, 1953
  - California
    - Whitmore v. Southern Pac. Co., 1951
  - Florida
    - City of Jacksonville v. Watkins, 1946
    - Herndon v. Tallahassee Transit Co., 1957
    - Taylor v. Seaboard Air Line R.R., 1953
  - Georgia
    - Coke v. City of Atlanta, 1958-1960
  - Illinois
    - Johnson v. Illinois Cent. R.R., 1951
    - Ward v. Chicago & E. Ill. R.R., 1951
  - Maryland
    - Henderson v. United States, 1950
  - New York
    - Jackson v. Seaboard Air Line Ry., 1947
  - New York
    - Morris v. Greyhound Corp., 1954
    - NAACP v. Saint Louis-San Francisco Ry., 1953
    - Worthy v. Louisville & Nashville R.R., 1948
  - North Carolina
    - Keys v. Carolina Coach Co., 1952-1961
  - South Carolina
    - Brown v. South Carolina Elec. and Gas Co., 1956
    - Flemming v. South Carolina Elec. and Gas Co., 1954-1956
  - Tennessee
    - Evers v. Dwyer, 1958
  - Virginia
    - Boynton v. Virginia, 1959-1960
    - Brown v. Southern R.R. Co., 1947 (and other southern states)
    - Day v. Atlantic Greyhound Corp., 1948
    - Roberts v. Seaboard Air Line Ry., 1944
    - Virginia v. Carolina Coach Co., 1950
    - Virginia v. Simms, 1951
    - Virginia v. Wilson, 1953
    - Williams v. Carolina Coach Co., 1953
  - West Virginia
    - Brown v. County Court of Kanawha County, W.Va., circa 1959
    - Brown v. Hanna, 1945